[{"Question":"What is the minimum number of infectious virus particles needed to make somone sick with the flu?","Correct Answer":3,"Choice 1":20,"Choice 2":9,"Choice 3":100,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What is not a way that diseases are transmitted?","Correct Answer":"eye-contact","Choice 1":"droplet","Choice 2":"aerosol","Choice 3":"fecal-oral","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What disease has been eradicated?","Correct Answer":"smallpox","Choice 1":"anthrax","Choice 2":"tuberculosis","Choice 3":"heart disease","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"Can a virus be treated with antibiotics?","Correct Answer":"No","Choice 1":"Yes","Choice 2":"Sometimes","Choice 3":"Only the flu","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What is a fomite?","Correct Answer":"An object likely to carry infectious material","Choice 1":"{A state of the art mask, An eradicated disease, Something used at a hospital, An object likely to carry infectious material}","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What city is it believed that the COVID-19 outbreak start in?","Correct Answer":"Wuhan","Choice 1":"Seoul","Choice 2":"London","Choice 3":"New York City","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What is a coronavirus?","Correct Answer":"A virus that causes an infection in your nose, sinuses, or throat","Choice 1":"A skin infection","Choice 2":"A type of broken bone","Choice 3":"A bacterial disease","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"COVID-19 is a type of coronavirus?","Correct Answer":true,"Choice 1":"False ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"COVID-19 is the only type of coronavirus?","Correct Answer":false,"Choice 1":"True ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What is another type of coronavirus?","Correct Answer":"MERS","Choice 1":"TB","Choice 2":"COPD","Choice 3":"HIV","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What country did the COVID-19 pandemic begin in?","Correct Answer":"China","Choice 1":"United States","Choice 2":"Argentina","Choice 3":"Somalia","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"How long should you wash your hands for?","Correct Answer":"20 seconds","Choice 1":"5 minutes ","Choice 2":"45 seconds ","Choice 3":"5 seconds","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"How many times should you sing Happy Birthday while washing your hands?","Correct Answer":"Twice","Choice 1":"8 times ","Choice 2":"Once","Choice 3":"It doesn't matter","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":null},{"Question":"What's the best way to wash your hands?","Correct Answer":"By using soap and water, because the soap helps lifts more dirt and bacteria off your hands.","Choice 1":"Just water. Soap isn't necessary.","Choice 2":"With no soap and only cold water to kill any bacteria on your hands.","Choice 3":"It doesn't matter. Water by itself s just as good as water and soap together.","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":null},{"Question":"Which virus or disease was not discovered during the past 100 years?","Correct Answer":"Tuberculosis","Choice 1":"Ebola","Choice 2":"HIV","Choice 3":"SARS","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What is herd immunity?","Correct Answer":"When most of the population is immune to an infectious disease and this protects the people who have not yet had it. ","Choice 1":"When the people who are sick from an infectious disease isolate themselves in a community, called a \"herd,\"  to protect those who are not yet sick.","Choice 2":"High Estimate of Residual Disease (HERD) Immunity","Choice 3":"When doctors form groups, called \"herds,\" to immunize large populations.","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What is the minimum percent of the population should have herd immunity to stop the spread of disease?","Correct Answer":0.8,"Choice 1":0.25,"Choice 2":0.99999,"Choice 3":0.5,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"Which disease does not have an effective vaccine?","Correct Answer":"Tuberculosis","Choice 1":"Polio","Choice 2":"Chickenpox","Choice 3":"Measles","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"What is the scientific name of the virus that causes COVID-19?","Correct Answer":"SARS-CoV-2","Choice 1":"HIV","Choice 2":"MERS-CoV","Choice 3":"COVID-19","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Where does the name \"corona\"-virus come from?","Correct Answer":"Under a microscope the virus has a halo called a  \"corona.\" ","Choice 1":"The scientist who discovered the first coronavirus liked Corona beer.","Choice 2":"The coronavirus family has the the \"kings\" of viruses. The word \"corona\" means \"crown\" in Greek.","Choice 3":"Corona was the name of the city in which the first Coronavirus was discovered.","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What common drug has been shown to reduced mortality for COVID-19 patients?","Correct Answer":"Dexamethasone","Choice 1":"Hydroxychloroquine","Choice 2":"Amoxicillin","Choice 3":"Aviane","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What non-invasive practice reduces the chance that a COVID-19 patient will have to use a ventilator?","Correct Answer":"Proning (placing patients on their stomaches)","Choice 1":"IV Fluids","Choice 2":"Nicotine Patches","Choice 3":"Intubations","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"How many coronaviruses infect humans?","Correct Answer":7,"Choice 1":3,"Choice 2":1,"Choice 3":10,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Which coronavirus is most deadly in humans?","Correct Answer":"MERS","Choice 1":"SARS","Choice 2":"COVID-19","Choice 3":"Ebola","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What country did the 2012 MERS outbreak begin in?","Correct Answer":"Jordan","Choice 1":"Saudi Arabia","Choice 2":"China","Choice 3":"France","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What country first reported cases of MERS in 2012","Correct Answer":"Saudi Arabia","Choice 1":"Jordan","Choice 2":"China","Choice 3":"United States","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What animal is suspected to be a resevoir host of MERS? (A resevoir host is an animal who carries a virus or bacteria.)","Correct Answer":"Camels","Choice 1":"Bats","Choice 2":"Ferrets","Choice 3":"Armadillo","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Is a virus alive?","Correct Answer":"No","Choice 1":"Yes","Choice 2":"Only in a host.","Choice 3":"It depends on the virus.","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "},{"Question":"Drinking lots of orange juice can help prevent the spread of COVID-19.","Correct Answer":false,"Choice 1":"True ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Why does wearing a mask help prevent the spread of COVID-19?","Correct Answer":"It prevents you from exhaling nfected droplets onto someone else and keeps you safe from accidentally inhaling someone else's infected droplets.","Choice 1":"It makes you look unfriendly so people are less likely to get near you, and thus less likely to infect you.","Choice 2":"It doesn't. People who think it does are delusional.","Choice 3":"It only helps when someone is symptomatic (coughing or sneezing).","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"A mask is effective when it covers just your mouth and not your nose.","Correct Answer":false,"Choice 1":"True ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Only medical grade masks are effective. Cloth masks do not prevent the spread of COVID-19.","Correct Answer":false,"Choice 1":"True ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Who should carry garlic to prevent the coronavirus?","Correct Answer":"No one.","Choice 1":"Vampires","Choice 2":"People in crowded areas. The garlic smell will make people less likely to get near you.","Choice 3":"Doctors","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"How many strains of COVID-19 have been identified?","Correct Answer":2,"Choice 1":5,"Choice 2":1,"Choice 3":3,"Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What is a possible complication of COVID-19?","Correct Answer":"Cytokine storm, or an uncontrolled inflamatry response. ","Choice 1":"T-cell mutilation","Choice 2":"Bone marrow collapse","Choice 3":"Vein atrophy","Difficulty":"Hard","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What is the most variable part of the coronavirus genome?","Correct Answer":"The Receptor Binding Domain (RBD) in the spike protein","Choice 1":"The virus shape ","Choice 2":"The Nuclear Capsule Structure (NCS)","Choice 3":"Membrane Elasticity Quotient (MEQ)","Difficulty":"Expert","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"What biosafety level must scientists studying SARS work in?","Correct Answer":"Level 2","Choice 1":"Level 1","Choice 2":"Level 3","Choice 3":"Level 4","Difficulty":"Expert","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Can COVID-19 be transmitted through a blood transfusion?","Correct Answer":"It is unlikely but scientists do not yet have enough data.","Choice 1":"Yes","Choice 2":"No","Choice 3":"Only if the person is highly infectious.","Difficulty":"Expert","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Scientists have confirmed that COVID-19 can be spread through droplets.","Correct Answer":true,"Choice 1":"False ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"Someone can become infected with COVID-19 by touching a surface someone who is sick with COVID-19 touched.","Correct Answer":true,"Choice 1":"False ","Choice 2":null,"Choice 3":null,"Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":true},{"Question":"How many viruses affect humans?","Correct Answer":"Over 200","Choice 1":"Less than 100","Choice 2":"Only COVID-19","Choice 3":"Too many to accurately identify.","Difficulty":"Easy","Answered ":false,"COVID Related":"False "}]